ILGWU. Carl Proper papers 5780/150
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Election Process (Publications), 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  Publications from the U.S. Dept. of Labor Labor- Management Services Administration: "Electing Union Officers," rev. 1980; and "Election of Officers of Labor Organizations," 1978; article, "The Election Base of National Union Executive Boards," by Sara Gamm, Industrial and Labor Relations Review, vol. 32, no. 3, April 1979 (Cornell University)
- I. Women (Box 8, Folder 13a)
- Reports: Congressional, General, 1981-1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  "Equal Opportunity for Women as a Federal Goal," United States Commission on Civil Rights (?), 1981; "The Role of Older Women in the Workforce," hearing before the Joint Economic Committee, Congress of the United States, June 6, 1984; "Problems of Working Women," hearing, April 3, 1984; Bureau of National Affairs articles, including statements by Rep. Olympia Snowe (R.-Maine) and deputy director, Census Bureau, before the Joint Economic Committee on Women in Workforce, 1983; "Economic Growth and Changing Labor Markets: Those Left Behind," Linda LeGrande, Congressional Research Service, Report No. 84-112 E, June 22, 1984; "Womena world survey," Ruth Leger Sivard, World Priorities, 1985; "Women, Work and Age Discrimination," Janice DeGooyer, prepared for the National Commission on Working Women, c. 1983; Congressional Record minutes of House proceedings re the Economic Equity Act of 1985 Retirement Security, June 6, 1985; Congressional Caucus for Women's Issues Update, May 31, 1983; press releases, News from WREI, Women's Research and Education Institute, re congressional fellowships, new publications, September 1987
- Reports: U.S. Labor Department, Labor Union, 1980-1987 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  Remarks by Wilbur Daniels, executive vice president, ILGWU, before the Women's Equity Action League, October 9, 1985; AFL-CIO Special Report: Female Organizing Focus, Union Labor Report, February 5, 1981; Proceedings of the Fifteenth Constitutional Convention of the AFL-CIO, Daily Proceedings and Executive Council Reports, October 3-6, 1983; Resolutions Adopted by the 16th Constitutional Convention of the Industrial Union Department (AFL-CIO), October 3-4, 1984; "Women at Work and in the Labor Movement: A Select Biography to Celebrate National Women's History Month," AFL-CIO Library, March 1990; teaching aid, "Women in the American Labor Movement: Yesterday & Today," Karin Gerstel, educational coordinator, NTRTP and ACTWU, c. 1981; "New Challenges for Women Workers," Carolyn Jacobson, AFL-CIO Federationist, April 1980; "Problems of Women Workers," 1981; "Economic Responsibilities of Working Women," U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau, November 1982; "Working Women and Public Policy," address by Dr. Janet L. Norwood, Commissioner of Labor Statistics, U.S. Department of Labor, at the National Conference on Women, the Economy and Public Policy, June 20, 1984; "Women's Bureau: Meeting the Challenges of the 80's," U.S. Department of Labor, 1985; "Where to Find BLS Statistics on Women," U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, April 1989; "20 Facts on Women Workers," U.S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau, 1984; Labor Relations Reporter summary of Office of Technology Assessment report, "Women in Science, Engineering," January 6, 1986; "Employment in Perspective: Women in the Labor Force," second quarter 1985 and fourth quarter 1986, U.S. Department of Labor Bureau of Labor Statistics; Women & Work, news from the U.S. Department of Labor, January 1987; A Woman's Guide to Social Security", U.S. Dept. of Health and Human Services, June 1983; Bureau of Labor Statistics data
- Articles, 1981-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Economic Council of Canada magazine, Au Courant, Women in the Labour Market, 1985; "Women at Work: Gender and Inequality in the '80s," a Dollars & Sense Anthology; Monthly Labor Review articles: "Moonlighting by Women Jumped to Record Highs," by John Stinson, Jr., November 1986, and "The Female-Male Unemployment Differential: Effects of Changes in Industry Employment," by Larry DeBoer and Michael Seeborg, November 1984; excepted chapter on the U.S., by Barbara Mayer Wertheimer, from Women and Trade Unions in Eleven Industrialized Countries, edited by Alice H. Cook, Val R. Lorwin, and Arlene Kaplan Daniels, n.d.; ILR Report, Cornell University, fall 1985, Special Report: What's New at the Office? "Women and the Office: A Historical Perspective," by Margery W. Davies; excerpted chapter on the U.S., by James J. Kenneally, from The World of Women's Trade Unionism: Comparative Historical Essays, edited by Norbert C. Soldon, 1985; "Technological Change in the Office Workplace and Implications for Organizing," by Judith Gregory, from Labor and Technology: Union Response to Changing Environments, Kennedy et al., State College, PA: Pennsylvania State University, Department of Labor Studies, 1982; "Teaching Sedition: Some Dilemmas of Feminist Pedagogy," report from the Center for Philosophy & Public Policy, University of Maryland, fall 1984; article by ILGWU official Gus Tyler re U.N. Nairobi conference on women, August 12, 1985; Business Week cover story, "Women at Work: They've Reshaped the Economy And Now Their Wages Will Rise," January 28, 1985, and other newspaper clippings from the New York Times, New Republic, Daily World, In These Times, 1983-85
- Comparable Worth, Wage Gap, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Report by the U.S. General Accounting Office: Comments on Report on Comparable Worth by the United States Commission on Civil Rights, September 1985; Civil Rights Commission New Perspectives issue on equal right for women, including comparable worth, spring 1985; Pay Equity Trends newsletters, re Yale University pay-equity strike, political party differences, September, November 1984; U.S. Department of Labor Bureau of Labor Statistics News, 1985; "An Economic Analysis of Comparable Worth," by Elaine Sorensen, New Labor Review, fall 1982; "Replacing the Marketplace: The Trouble with Comparable Worth," by Jean Yarbrough, The New Leader, November 26, 1984; "Comparable Worth: In Praise of Muddling Through," by Sar A. Levitan and Clifford M. Johnson, The Journal of the Institute for Socioeconomic Studies, summer 1985; concluding chapter of Comparable Worth and Wage Discrimination: Technical Possibilities and Political Realities, edited by Helen Remick, Temple University Pres, 1984; supplementary statement by ILGWU official Gus Tyler to Women, Work, and Wages: Equal Pay for Jobs of Equal Value, National Research Council, 1981; "Investigating the Differences in Weekly Earnings of Women and Men," by Earl F. Mellor, Monthly Labor Review, June 1984; "The Trend in the Male-Female Wage Gap in the United States," by June O'Neill, Journal of Labor Economics, 1985; "Comparable Worth: Where Do We Go from Here? Research Needs in Comparable Worth," Heidi I. Hartmann, published in Industrial Relations Research Association Series Proceedings of the Thirty-Seventh Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1984; ILGWU staff memo, "What Is Comparable Worth and How Does It Affect Workers in the Garment Industry?" June 1984; Bureau of National Affairs, Labor Relations Reporter, and Monthly Labor Review articles, 1985; newspaper clippings, many re U.N. Nairobi conference on women
- Workfoce Quality and Skills Training, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Invitation to ILG president Mazur to testify at public hearing sponsored by the U.S. Secretary of Labor's Commission on Workforce Quality and Labor Market Efficiency, with outline of topics of interest, March 22, 1989; Bureau of National Affairs article, "Advisory Committee Tentatively Agrees on Suggestions to Improve U.S. Workforce," 1989; report, "Working Capital: JTPA Investments for the 90's," A Report of the Job Training Partnership Act Advisory Committee, March 1989; correspondence; newspaper clipping
- III. Companies (Box 9, Folder 3a)
- Andmore Sportswear, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Export Trade Development Projects Program client reporting form; nomination form for Commissioner's Award to Recognize Outstanding Human Resources Practices in the Apparel Manufacturing Industry, with description of Port Jervis, NY-based firm, noting labor-management committee; correspondence from Fashion Exports New York and Council for American Fashion (CAF) re expanding export of racing swimwear, especially to Japan; CAF memo to ILGWU business agent analyzing new Andmore piece-rate pay system; skills training grant approval notification from NYS Dept. of Economic Development; handwritten notes
- Avalon Classics, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Export Trade Development Projects Program client reporting form, noting that New York-based jobber wished to export to Europe and Asia; list of contractors jobs for selected jobbers
- Carolyne Roehm, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Newspaper clippings re closing of the high-end line; lacked adequate licensing agreements
- Cuddle Teen Frocks, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Client registration form for exporting, with description of New York-based company (manufactured 100% domestically) and its attitude toward exporting and competition in the popular-priced segment (sold to Sears, JC Penny, Target, Kmart, U.S. armed forces); list, contractor jobs created by jobber or manufacturer
- Fairbrooke Enterprises, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  Full-page ad in Women's Wear Daily responding to article "For Wool Coats, It's a Struggle Just to Survive," January 16, 1990
- Finity Sportswear, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  List, contractor Jobs for Jobbers; ad from Saks
- Gabar, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, Gabar President and Carl Proper; Gabar contact information; Export Trade Development Projects Program Client Reporting Form; magazine clippings
- Gelfo, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Memo from the Council for American Fashion re interview with company management by FIT professor; notes company is being bled dry as cash cow for parent; no upgrades provided
- Gloria Sachs, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Article re closing of company
- H.W. Jan Enterprises, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  Apparel Survey I: Contractors to help the Labor-Management Committee for the New Jersey Apparel Industry and the NJIT Center for Manufacturing Systems increases competitiveness
- Hesteco Manufacturing, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Memos re Hummelstown, PA-based company, certified for Federal Trade Adjustment Assistance for losses to imports; principal jobber, Cuddle Teen, dropped contract for cheaper overseas suppliers. Description of company; handwritten notes by CAF director Carl Proper; newspaper clipping re closure.
- Intimate Apparel, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  Data on intimate apparel firms, contractors, jobbers for local 62-32; newspaper clippings
- Leslie Fay, 1986-1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Annual report, 1986; reprint from Bobbin, "The Union's Call for Cooperation," by ILGWU president Jay Mazur, August 1990; Apparel Industry Magazine opinion piece by Leslie Fay president Michael Babcock, criticizing ILGWU practice of charging penalty fees to manufacturers for imports and nonunion subcontractors, August 1994; lists of inside shops and major contractors, 1990-92; agreement applying to plants covered by the Pennsylvania Supplemental Agreement, 1992; arbitration demand over pressuring contractors to lower prices, April 29, 1992; Women's Wear Daily clipping profiling chief financial officer Paul Polishan, February 9, 1989; newspaper clippings re Chapter 11 bankruptcy after accounting fraud misstated earnings, closure of last U.S. plant, 1995
- Ornstein Fashions, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Apparel Survey I: Contractors to help the Labor-Management Committee for the New Jersey Apparel Industry and the NJIT Center for Manufacturing Systems increases competitiveness for Garfield, NJ-based firm; letter from La Ventaja, Inc., inviting Harvey Ornstein to take advantage of LVA's shelter services eliminating legal risks and maximizing operational flexibility and cost savings through manufacturing in Mexico, with handwritten note, "I already bought my sombrero"
- Pantagis, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Export Trade Development Projects Program Client Reporting Form; list, Contractor Jobs for Selected Jobbers; newspaper clippings
- Party Formals/After Five, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Nomination of Party Formals president as Crain's All-Star by ILG president Mazur, January 29, 1992; Export Trade Development Projects Program Client Reporting Form; company press releases, newspaper clipping
- Saramae/Iris Lingerie, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Export Trade Development Projects Program Client Reporting Form; located in New York City and West Newark, NJ
- Schrader, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Newspaper clippings re purchase of label licensing by Kenar Enterprises
- IV. Organizations (Box 9, Folder 21a)
- American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  Newsletters, AIFLD Outlook, article reprint
- Center for the Study of American Business, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  Working papers on trade/protectionism, decline of U.S. manufacturing, and revival of the rust belt
- Council on International and Public Affairs, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  Press releases on decline in real wages, U.S. jobs situation
- Council on Competitiveness, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  Nonpartisan coalition of business, labor, and academics. Legislative and Policy Update, Feb. 1, 1993
- Citizen Action, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  Copies of transparencies and scripts for slide show on the economy, "Calling Their Bluff on Unemployment and Inflation"; correspondence with Carl Proper; U.S. Department of Commerce News press releases; newspaper clipping re Reagan and the economy
- Crafted with Pride in the U.S.A. Council, Incorporated, 1985-1991 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  Coalition of U.S. cotton growers and man-made fiber producers, labor organizations, fabric distributors, and manufacturers of fabric, apparel, and home furnishings whose aim was to raise consumer awareness for looking for "Made in USA" labels. Press releases, brochure, newspaper clippings, speeches, consumer preference surveys, correspondence with advertising agency Carl Byoir & Associates, minutes of marketing committee meeting, July 24, 1990
- Ditchley Foundation, 1988-1993 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  Nonprofit British-based organization dedicated to the study great issues through the convening of conferences. General information on foundation; newsletters/conference reports/papers; invitation to ILG president Mazur to attend a conference on international relations 1990, with attached agenda and related materials; speech/talking points offered to Mazur by ILG director of research Starobin, "Economic Management in a Global Context"; newspaper clipping
- Dollars and Sense, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  Fundraising letters for progressive economics newsletter, 1992
- Economic Policy Council, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  A program of the United Nations Association of the USA. Agenda for first plenary session, October 1987; summary of meeting to ILG president Mazur by exec. asst. Parrott; member list
- A. Economic Policy Institute (Box 9, Folder 30a)
- Economic Policy Institute, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  Descriptions of institute, founded in 1986 as nonprofit think tank; list of funders, 1986-88; biography of president, Jeff Faux; letters to ILGWU president Mazur from EPI president Jeff Faux, thanking him for support, noting institute's goal as alternative voice to "voodoo economics"; memos to Mazur from exec. asst. Parrott re contributions, policy issues; letter from EPI to ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott with attached statement, sent to Congress, signed by 447 prominent economists opposing the Balanced Budget Amendment, June 12, 1992; letter from American Textile Manufacturers Institute re NAFTA, Aug. 19, 1992; EPI briefing paper, "The Myth of the Coming Labor Shortage in Rural Areas," by Ruy A. Teixeira and Lawrence Mishel, March 1992; list of conservative think tanks, Sept. 6, 1991; press releases, correspondence, newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Economic Policy Institute: Trade, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  Papers by University of Maryland business professor Robert E. Scott on trade, refuting book by William R. Cline; memo to ILG president Mazur from research director Herman Starobin discussing Cline book, with attached discussion by ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman, October 2, 1987; letter from Economic Policy Institute inviting ILG exec. asst. James Parrott to a luncheon discussion of research proposal of Prof. Scott; letter to researcher Richard Rothstein from institute, discussing statistics on displaced workers; handwritten notes re Scott proposal; draft of letter to the Washington Post by Prof. Scott refuting op-ed piece re trade protection, Sept. 18, 1990; correspondence, handwritten notes
- Economic Policy Institute, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  Letter from Secretary of Labor Elizabeth Dole re EPI report "Workforce Policies for the 1990s," March 2, 1989; letter to EPI from ILGWU research director Herman Starobin critiquing report by Richard Rothstein, "Keeping Jobs in Fashion: An Alternative to the Euthanasia of the U.S. Apparel Industry," with memo from ILGWU exec. asst. Parrott to pres. Mazur, Nov. 16, 1989, and related correspondence; letter to ILGWU exec. asst. Parrott asking him to sign "Economists' Statement in Support of Increased Public Investment," April 14, 1989; press releases, correspondence, newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Economic Policy Institute, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  Briefing paper, "Getting Rid of the Trade Deficit: A Cheaper Dollar Is Not Enough," by Jeff Faux, March 1988, and responses (press clippings, letters); invitation, agenda, and related materials for conference, "The First 100 Days," June 1988; correspondence, newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Economic Policy Institute, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  Invitation, agenda, and related materials for conference, "Trade, Competitiveness, and the American Standard of Living," March 1987, with registration request by ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott; draft of paper for presentation at EPI Seminar on the Measurement of Manufacturing Output, "Trends in Manufacturing's Level and Share of Output," by Lawrence Mishel, with invitation to ILGWU exec. asst. Parrott, November 1987; briefing paper, "Competitiveness and Balanced Budgets," July 1987; reprint from the World Policy Journal, "The Post Reagan Economy: A New Democratic Deal," by Jeff Faux, spring 1986; correspondence, newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Enterprise for the Americas Initiative, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Letter to ILG president Mazur from the U.S. Secretaries of Commerce and the Treasury re Bush administration program to foster economic growth in Latin America; related materials
- B. Fashion Institute of Technology (FIT) (Box 10, Folder 1a)
  see also "Technology -- FIT Advanced Apparel Manufacturing Technology Demonstration"
- Fashion Institute of Technology (FIT), 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Board of Trustees meeting minutes, Oct. 2, describing 11 grants received by FIT for vocational training; "Report on Locations for Apparel Manufacturing Research," listing academic sites nationwide, prepared for ILG by FIT Professor Irwin Kahn; memos to ILGWU president Mazur re issues discussed at meetings with FIT president Marvin Feldman; follow-up letter from Mazur to Feldman re combining efforts to develop management training programs, model production plant, inviting him to serve on Fashion Industries Economic Development Council; brochure, "An Invitation to AAMTD: Advanced Apparel Manufacturing Technology Demonstration," sponsored by the Defense Logistics Agency of the U.S. Department of Defense, associated newsletters re training program, proposed joint robotics program; memo re meeting with FIT professor Kahn re ESL program, model plant, computerized production courses; newsletter, "FIT Economic Development News"; resolution by ILGWU Local 23-25 commending FIT for assistance to GIDC; press releases and memos re FIT export conference
- Fashion Institute of Technology (FIT), 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  Memos re meetings with FIT president Marvin Feldman; agenda for seminar, "Key Issues of the 90s"; newsletters, newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Export Program, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Descriptive material re the FIT Export Advisory Extension Service; correspondence and publicity material for "Export with the Experts" workshop; list of exporters and potential exporters compiled by the Council for American Fashion (CAF) and Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC); brochures
- Skills Training, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Correspondence re March 29, 1990, meeting re entry-level sewing skills training program for women living in public homeless shelters; "A Report on Future Independence through Training at the Fashion Institute of Technology," November 1989; handwritten notes
- Federation for Industrial Renewal and Retention (FIRR), 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Coalition of labor unions and nonprofit groups concerned about plant closings. Correspondence and report re Industrial Renaissance Conference, 1989; membership list; annual report, Midwest Center for Labor Research, 1989-90; FIRR newsletter, spring 1991; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes
- Federation of Apparel Manufacturers (FAM), 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Testimony of Federation of Apparel Manufacturers before the New York City Council Committee on Economic Development, November 11, 1988; Remarks by Jay Mazur, New York Skirt and Sportswear, re commercial rent, GIDC, trade legislation, TC2, homework, October 20, 1988; statement of Eli Elias as executive director, New York Skirt and Sportswear Association, and testimony of Eli Elias as president of the Federation of Apparel Manufacturers (with list of members), to the House Subcommittee on Labor Standards, September 16, 1986, against lifting the ban on homework; letter from Somerset Knitting Mills, Inc., to the House Subcommittee on Labor Standards, against lifting the ban on homework, September 8, 1986; letter from FAM to NYC director of economic planning re zoning plan, May 23, 1986; newspaper clipping and trade reports re chargebacks; retail performance inquiry sheet
- Freedom House, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  Drafts of Statement on America in the Post-Cold War Era, a statement on the 50th anniversary of Freedom House; critical memos from ILG president Mazur and other ILG officials re wording of statement, anachronistic themes, simplistic characterization of the poor, economic and social issues; printed Freedom at Issue, "Freedom around the World: U.S. Policy & the U.N." January/February 1989
- C. Harvard Center for Apparel & Textile Research (Box 10, Folder 8a)
- Seminars, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  Reports: "A Profile of the Labor Market in the Apparel Industry," David Weil, December 18, 1990; "Allied, Federated, and Campeau: Causes, Outcomes, and Implications," Daniel M. G. Raff and Walter S. Salmon, Harvard Business School, January 1991; article reprint from Harvard Business Review by Salmon et al.; notes re key points of Salmon presentation; seminar agendas (with handwritten notes from presentations) re robotics and automation, human resources, logistics; letter re new director of Needle Trades Action Project, 1991; newspaper clippings
- Seminars: Mens Shirts, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  Workshop agenda, participant list, reports: "A Statistical Profile of the Men's Shirt Industry," "Improving the Performance of the Men's Dress Shirt Industry: A Channel Perspective," August 6-7, 1991; newspaper clippings, article reprint from Harvard Business School Bulletin, academic journal article
- International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (IFCTU), 1983-1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)